My Summary My phone number: (57-3218253959) caluss48@hotmail.com



I have worked as developer for almost 5 years in banking, insurance and telecommunications industries where I have used Java and JavaScript programming language and their technologies and frameworks such as Spring, springboot, jdbc and others.

Technologies

JAVA 1.7,	> J3EE	es.
1.8, 11,	HTML and	LIFERAY
and 1.9	css	6.2, 7.0
Spring,	Boostrap	and 7.2.
Springboot	Javascript,	Monololitic
,	jquery and	, and
springclou	Ajax.	microservi
d, y	SVN and	ces
springdata	Git	Architectur
SOAP and	Mysql,	e.
REST	Oracle and	Web logic
JPA, JDBC	Postrgres.	and
у	Sql querys	Tomcat.
Hibernate	> Scrum	Maven and
> JSF	Metodologi	gradle

AWS(Ama zone web services)
 Creacion de servicios y despliegue s en lambdas
 Jenkins
 SONAR
 Jira

Languages

Spanish (native speaker)

English (advanced)

Career History

Globant, Bogotá, Colombia

Semi Senior Java

Analize Bank requirements

- Design technical troubleshooting and document of microservices
- Develop microservices to the bank
- Develop and maintain springcloud components to microservice architecture.
- Work with Git repository, Bitbucket.
- Work under scrum methodologies.

Octuber. 2019 - Currently Java Semi Senior

SOPHOS SOLUTIONS, Bogotá, Colombia

Mar. 2020 – August. 2021

Expert Engineer

- Analize Customer requirements
- Develops and documents code according to the development process.
- Makes unit test with Junit and Mockito
- Develops web services with REST arquitecture, spring and springboot framework.
- Work LIFERAY Platform.
- Develop LIFERAY backend components such as portlets, servicebuilder and osgi mudules(Versions: 6.2, 7.0 and 7.2).
- Develop LIFERAY frontend components such as templates, structures and web components (Versions: 6.2, 7.0 and 7.2).
- Work with dependencies file such as Maven and Gradle.
- Work with Git repository and SVN.
- Work under scrum methodologies.

VASS LATAM, Bogotá, Colombia

Mar. 2019 – Mar. 2020

Development Engineer

- Analize Customer requirements
- Develops and documents code according to the development process.
- Makes unit test with Junit and Mockito
- Develops web services with REST arquitecture, and spring framework.
- Learn and Work LIFERAY Platform (Versions: 7.0).
- Develop LIFERAY components such as portlets, servicebuilder and osgi mudules.
- Work with dependencies file such as Maven and Gradle.
- Work with Git repository
- Work under scrum methodologies.

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Analize Bank requirements
- Design technical document of web services.
- Develops web services with Rest arquitecture, and spring framework.
- Work with Git repository
- Work under scrum methodologies.

INGENIAN SOFTWARE, Bogotá, Colombia

Jan. 2018 – Jan. 2019

Development Enginner

- Analyze customer requirements
- Develops software components with JSF framework, beans and JPA.
- Develops web services with SOAP and BROKER architecture.
- Work with SVN reposiotory.

Education

Politécnico Grancolombiano, Bogotá, Colombia

Jun. 2018 – Sept 2022

BS, Systems Engineering

SENA, Bogotá, Colombia

Jan. 2016 - Dec. 2018

TECHNOLOGIST, Information System Analysis and Development